MARY MALCOLM

Email: mljmalcolm@gmail.com • Mobile: 336-491-9350 • High Point, NC 27265

Links: LinkedIn • Portfolio Site

Summary

Creative professional with marketing, web and graphic design experience, and a genuine interest in continuous learning. Highly self-motivated, organized problem solver, with a proven ability to juggle multiple priorities, projects and deadlines.

Skills

Microsoft Office • InDesign • Illustrator • Acrobat • HTML • CSS • E-commerce: Miva Merchant CMS: Wordpress, Mura • Google Analytics • Google AdWords • SEO / SEM • FTP • Vertical Response

Professional Experience

International Market Centers, High Point, NC; Las Vegas, NV, Advertising Production Specialist (2011-2018)

- Designed client advertisements for print publications and large format signs.
- Designed and updated sales sheets, spec sheets, mockups, media kits, direct mail.
- Scheduled and assisted in design and implementation of email marketing campaigns.
- Maintained comprehensive sponsorship inventory for quarterly tradeshows in two cities.
- Coordinated with printers and sign installers regarding specs, ad installation, and placement.
- Assisted account executives and clients with ad specification and design inquiries.
- Proofread all marketing materials and tradeshow publications.
- Streamlined and implemented new ad routing and proofing processes.
- Assisted in development, testing, and implementation of art file submission website.
- Managed multiple websites during company mergers (2007–2012).

International Market Centers, High Point, NC, Marketing Coordinator / IT Manager (2007–2011)

- Managed all aspects of print and digital ads for quarterly tradeshow publications and sponsorships.
- Managed servers, Active Directory; maintained daily performance of network and computer systems.
- Provided technical support to employees related to computer hardware and software.
- Coordinated employee software training classes and documented step-by-step procedures.
- Supported advertising production manager.

Alabama Heritage, University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa, AL, Marketing Assistant (2001-2007)

- Maintained company website, managed/merchandised ecommerce website (Miva Merchant).
- Designed print and digital ads, logos, and graphics.
- Created and distributed E-mail newsletters.

MLCreations Handcrafted Jewelry, Northport, AL, Owner/Designer (2001-2009)

- Designed, built, marketed E-commerce website, email newsletter, managed eBay store.
- Designed, managed, maintained company websites for local small businesses.

Certifications

Practical JavaScript Premium Course-watchandcode.com, (expected completion Dec, 2019)
Practical JavaScript-watchandcode.com, 2019
freeCodeCamp.org, 2019, Responsive Web Design Certification
Lynda.com, 2013-2016, 22 certificates: graphic design, print production, InDesign, Illustrator

Education

William Rainey Harper College, Palatine, IL, 1998, Associate in Arts Anne Arundel Community College, Arnold, MD, 1997